[Music]
foreign
this is RAM and I'm a co-founder and
director of mad over insurance
say we eat sleep think only insurance
so we are bringing you
interesting videos related to insurance
and customer experiences
please subscribe to our YouTube channel
mad over insurance and also follow our
website www dot madoverinsurance.com and
also our social platforms
good morning
let's look at surti bonds for
infrastructure projects
the budget for 2022-23
allowed the use of shooty bonds
in place of Bank guarantee for any
government procurement
SRI nitin gadkari
Union Minister for Road Transport and
highways
launch India's first ever surety bond
insurance product that from Bajaj
Allianz
let's briefly understand what a surety
bond insurance is
if you look at a surety bond insurance
The Surety we have a one party which is
called The Surety
it's a neutral party
like an insurance company
which guarantees the contractor's
obligation towards the principal
then we have the contractor
the party who's required to obtain the
shuty bond
example a contractor undertaking large
in Frost projects
then we have the principal who is
awarding that contract
who is requiring that contractor to
obtain the surety bond
example of a principle could be NHA or
the national highway authority of India
what are the advantages of surety bond
over Bank guarantee
normally surety bond requires lower
collaterals due which due to which the
capital the contact of the contractor
gets released
contractors can use working capital more
effectively
to understand the shooty bond insurance
in detail
normally Insurance part policies have
two parties one is the buyer of
insurance other is the seller of
insurance
however surety bond insurance has three
parties as we had seen we had the
principal we had the contractor we had
The Surety
normally whenever any infras project is
given
there is a contract between the
principal and the contractor for the
construction works
if the contractor fails to comply with
any of the conditions of the contract
then the principal invokes the bank
guarantee
if surety bond insurance is taken place
in place of Bank guarantee
the bond would be called upon by the
principal and the insurance company
would make the payment to the principal
insurance company after paying to the
claim has subrogation rights based on
which insurer will try to recover the
losses from the contractor
y bond insurance can be conditional or
unconditional if it is unconditional it
is as good as a bank guarantee
but if it's a conditional Insurance
wording then insurance companies
settless the claim only after satisfying
itself about the allegations of breach
and the Quantum of laws suffered by the
principal
there can be many different types of
shooty bonds some of the different
Insurance products are one is called the
big Bond second is called the
performance bond and third is called the
maintenance Bond
if bidder is awarded contract he does
not accept the contract this policy pays
compensation to the principal
in the performance bond if the
contractor defaults on the contract um
then this Bond will pay to the principal
in the maintenance Bond if the
contractor fails to remedy defects as as
per the defects liability terms of the
contract then the bond will be paid to
the principal
one question that comes up will really
the surety bond insurance succeed in
India
if the shuty bond insurance has to
succeed
governmental agencies like the national
highway authority of India
how to make the shooty bond wording a
part of the tender document
second important thing is assessing the
risk is a very very specialized subject
banks have better resources than
insurance companies
insurance companies need specialized
Underwriters for this
and if the shuty bond insurance has to
succeed reinsurance support is very very
critical
if these fat three factors are fulfilled
there is a chance of the surety bond
insurance succeeding in the market
thank you
[Music]
foreign